Contact

roy.martinezblanco@gmail.com

Phone: +506 8712-3196

www.linkedin.com/in/ roymartinezblanco (LinkedIn) roymartinez.dev/ (Personal)

Top Skills

Enterprise Architecture
Cloud Computing
Content Delivery Network

Languages

Spanish

English

Certifications

- AWS Certified Solutions
- Architect Associate
- AWS Certified Cloud

Practitioner

- Akamai:
 - API Gateway
 - Image Manager
 - DevOps
- Red Hat Core

Administration Certification

- Splunk Certified

Honors-Awards

Best Engineer/ Consultant Spot Award 2014 to 2018

Roy Martinez Blanco

Content Delivery Network Expert | Cloud Architect |
Enterprise Architect, Web Performance | AWS-SAA | Entrepreneur

Summary

Cloud and Content Delivery Network expert, a Computer analyst with strong communication, leadership skills, and strong technical background. Used to frequent customer contact, working with people from diverse backgrounds and responsibilities.

I handle pre-sales, implementation and Escalation point and Technical expert, leading on calls with customers, demos, on-site training, Conferences, QBR's, Architecture reviews, etc.

I am used to working under pressure and in a multinational environment where the proactive and fast learn competencies are vital to ensure the work is done with the best quality possible.

Experience

Akamai Technologies
Enterprise Architect, Web Performance
July 2018 - Present
Costa Rica

Architect/Design and document complex solutions (Infrastructure, Web Performance, Zero Trust, Availability, etc) that require the participation of multiple organizations

Provide consulting services to key decision makers and designs for the development of enterprise customers. Analyze site performance and business effectiveness of web sites, mobile web sites, and mobile apps, with a focus on helping customers optimize their sites for maximum conversion and revenue through the use of tools like DataScience. Acting as the highest service escalation point for platform and production performance issues.

Build strategic roadmaps with customers to meet their business objectives and achieve increased value from their investment in Akamai.

Establish a high standard of leadership – provide subject matter expertise for new products to the rest of the organization, and research, establish, and disseminate industry trends.

Dreamplay Costa Rica Co-Founder/CTO August 2016 - Present San Jose, Costa Rica

Brindamos un servicio profesional completo, donde basado en las necesidades de su empresa nuestro equipo es adaptado para brindar una experiencia personalizada única. Nuestro equipo de realidad virtual puede ser utilizado para actividades tales como activaciones, eventos, giras educativas, promoción de marca, entre otras.

Akamai Technologies
5 years 1 month
Senior Solutions Architect
March 2017 - July 2018 (1 year 5 months)
Costa Rica

++SAII..SME for web delivery products and web optimization because of this I work with product teams to drive their projects, usually the sought out person to work on a new release/product/beta and go to person for high complex scenarios without the need of much scoping since capable of thinking outside of the box. Team lead for local and global solution architects, and documentation evangelist for multiple products. Constantly creating custom solution/implementations that are outside of the scope of our productos but within the capabilities of the platform and because of this I implement this solutions on advance logic/Metadata to meet our customer expectations.

Solutions Architect II September 2015 - March 2017 (1 year 7 months) Lindora Park, Santa Ana, San José, Costa Rica

++SA .. As a experienced SA II was constantly training new hires, as well doing onsite customer visits to train them on any product and even delivering custom topics. Any complex implementation or unknown environment that had challenges to have it implemented within the platform was owned and passed on to me. As well major accounts that required a lot of expertise and carefulness due to the contract that had in between was passed on to Senior SAs and me. Constantly collaborate with cross functional teams to prepare

documentation and proactively work towards the mitigation of identified risks and roadblocks.

Solutions Architect

July 2013 - September 2015 (2 years 3 months)

Escazú Corporate Center, 8th floor, Escazú, San José, Costa Rica, 10201

As a Solutions Architect I am part of the Akamai Service Delivery team and work directly with clients to deliver Akamai's solutions. Being involved with projects from requirements gathering, design, implementation, testing and customer sign-off. I usually work independently or within a global technical team in delivering the appropriate solution to Akamai's customers. The day to day includes plan, implement, test, and deploy Akamai platform configurations to integrate our customers' web sites with the Akamai Intelligent Platform, develop and execute test cases and scripts for customer solutions.

Responsibilities:

Work as a member of a cross-functional project team contributing to the technology-based solutions and consult on concept feasibility.

- * Own the technical components of a customer integration project including but not limited to design, configuration, debugging, documentation, testing, and go live support.
- * Integrate Akamai's Solutions including media, acceleration, downloads and security products.
- * Partner with Business Support, Sales, Engineering, Product Development and Customer Care to resolve issues that arise during customer trials, integrations, or post implementation support.
- * Identify technical risks and provide mitigation strategies.

Hewlett-Packard

3 years 3 months

(DEVOPS)Operations Support Engineer

June 2012 - June 2013 (1 year 1 month)

Costa Rica

As DEVOPS Engineer my work was focused on process automation. This meant developing software that was used by the support staff and managers. The software facilitated and increases productivity, for the BU (Enterprise Storage, Servers and Networking). Thanks to the development we were able to capture metric data to create reports that was provided to Senior management and to the agents as their score cards. This meant that I also maintained all

Application servers, Databases, managed communication to the staff of all levels about all news or activities about the tools developed and also owned all project management activities. All software's developed were done with .NET due to HP's alignment to Microsoft products.

Disk Storage Engineer April 2010 - June 2012 (2 years 3 months)

Technical Solutions Cons II, for the Storage account Online Disk. Hicomplex with various operating system (HP-UX, OpenVMS, WSS 2k3 /2k8) supporting storage servers, disk enclosures, switches, Hardware and software. Knowledge in different protocols fiber channel, SAS, SCSI and ISCSI etc.

Designed websites to facilitate and increase productivity of the team. Trained/Mentored new Engineer's

Stream Global Services
Technical Support
December 2008 - April 2010 (1 year 5 months)

Worked at Stream Global Services as tech support Tier 2 for Time Warner Cable and also Acting Senior Support Professional, Floor Support and experienced at giving trainings, Team Manager Back up (Quality evaluations, Stats reports).

Education

Universidad Americana (CR) Systems Engineering · (2011 - 2014)

Universidad Latinoamericana de Ciencia y Tecnología WebMaster, Web Page, Digital/Multimedia and Information Resources Design · (2013 - 2013)

Colegio de Santa Ana

High School diploma Colegio de Santa Ana · (2006 - 2008)